Nate Yolles

Mountain View, CA 94043 https://www.linkedin.com/in/nateyolles https://github.com/nateyolles 562-715-5371 (cell) nate@nateyolles.com @nateyolles

Summary

Adobe Experience Manager (AEM/CQ) engineer with experience implementing the CMS platform for some of Silicon Valley's top companies. Manager and technical team lead dedicated to innovation and AEM best practices. AEM and Apache Sling open source contributor. Twenty years of experience building interactive web applications. Focused on increasing SEO, speed and responsiveness of websites through the use optimized graphic design, valid markup, organized CSS, and efficient JavaScript ultimately realizing rich user experiences. Experienced working closely with offshore teams, agile, scrum, and waterfall development methodologies.

Technical Skills

Server-Side: AEM/CQ, Apache Sling, JCR (Apache Jackrabbit/Oak), OSGI (Apache Felix), Java,

JSP, Sightly, JavaScript, Apache Web Server, Dispatcher

Client-Side: HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS, Compass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX,

JSON, MVC/MVVM frameworks (Angular, Knockout, Mustache, Handlebars)

Tools: Git, SVN, Jira, Artifactory, Jenkins, Mayen, Akamai CDN, GruntJS, ReviewBoard,

Linux, Amazon AWS, Adobe Photoshop, AEM Campaigns and Target

Methodologies: Agile, Scrum

Professional Experience

AEM Engineering Manager, Adobe Document Cloud

Adobe Systems, Inc. San Jose, CA

- Lead architect and engineering manager for Adobe's Document Cloud marketing websites.
- Manage engineering and QA resources
- Support acrobat.adobe.com, acrobat.com and echosign.com.
- AEM 6.2 migration
- Implemented and guided Agile Scrum processes
- Designed and implement web production and content release workflows
- Implemented peer code reviews
- Structured release processes

Lead AEM/CQ Engineer, Adobe Document Cloud

Adobe Systems, Inc.

June 2014 – November 2015 San Jose, CA

November 2015 – Present

- Architect the AEM marketing sites for Adobe's Document Cloud including Acrobat at acrobat.adobe.com (AEM 6)
- Maintain and develop for acrobat.com (AEM 5.6.1) and echosign.com (AEM 5.4)
- Maintain the host servers on Amazon AWS EC2 instances
- Maintain AEM instances, services, hot fixes, service packs and updates
- Create release scripts and manage launches
- Manage Akamai CDN cache
- Manage Apache web server, Dispatcher filters, redirects, and caching strategies
- Manage continuous integration with Jenkins
- Create easy to use and maintain Sightly and JSP components
- Create services and servlets
- Manage AEM users and assist web producers (authors)

- Work with SEO, Target, and Campaign teams to optimize sales
- Manage performance optimizations
- Introduce and coach Agile and Scrum processes
- Instruct and guide on AEM best practices

AEM/CQ5 Developer

LinkedIn, Corp.

May 2013 – June 2014 Mountain View, CA

- Maintain company subdomain websites that represents the main revenue branches: business.linkedin.com, sales.linkedin.com, marketing.linkedin.com, talent.linkedin.com, and premium.linkedin.com
- Support the Adobe AEM/CQ5 CMS platform that hosts the company's marketing and sales campaigns
- Deliver timely and targeted marketing websites such as the Veterans Day website and the China Launch Video Landing page
- Secure platform from XSS attacks thus eliminating the need for security content review
- Performance optimizations including reducing Time To First Byte from 2.2 seconds to 120 milliseconds
- Implement SEO, analytics, click event tracking, and real user metrics
- Maintain the codebase and the Java Content Repository (JCR) using Apache Jackrabbit, Sling, OSGi bundles, Maven, and XPath
- Introduced separation of presentation and business logic layers by moving logic from JSP to Java classes, services, and servlets
- Utilize AJAX, JSON, and REST APIs
- Introduced custom JSTL tag library and EL functions
- Support LinkedIn's marketing and sales teams

Web Developer, UX Tech Specialist

Word & Brown, Inc.

Dec. 2006 – May 2013 Orange, CA

- Enterprise team member responsible for UI, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript standards and practices
- Helped deliver the Affordable Care Act Healthcare Exchanges for the states of Nevada and Florida serving tens of millions of people, utilizing the KnockoutJS MVVM framework and .NET MVC.
- Single page applications
- Graphic design, layouts, mockups and wireframes for web applications
- Design and create the UI for web applications in the .NET environment
- Create UI for desktop and click-once applications
- Mobile web development for iPhone, iPad, and Android devices
- Create .NET custom and user controls, master pages and forms
- Generate minified and concatenated CSS and JavaScript

Web Developer, PHP Programmer

Independent Consultant

Jan. 2001 – Dec. 2006 Orange County, CA

- Served realtors from Tarbell, RE/MAX, and Keller Williams
- Graphic design for websites, logos, posters, signs, flyers, business cards, and mailers
- Brand recognition
- Develop websites in PHP
- Implement eCommerce payment and shopping cart systems
- Administer databases in MySQL
- Maintain LINUX servers

• Search Engine Optimization and Google Analytics

Web Developer

KeepSmart / SmartPros

Jun. 1997 – Jan. 2001 Irvine, CA

- Website development
- Graphical User Interfaces (GUI) for online, interactive learning courses
- Graphic design for web and print
- Flash animations and presentations

Education

1998 – 2003	California State University, Long Beach Bachelor of Arts Degree Film & Electronic Arts Major Classes in C++ and Java President's Honor List for 4.0 GPA semesters Dean's List for 3.5 GPA semesters
Certification	
2015	Certified ScrumMaster Scrum Alliance
2015	Certified Product Owner

2014 Oracle Certified Java Programmer I

Scrum Alliance

100% test score